


<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Douglas&apos; Blog</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 14:08:04 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 14:08:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience with Supabase</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished up a quick project for an assignment. I had to make a simple app that utilizes a database. I wrote the app in React Native using the Expo framework. The actual writing of the app I was not worried about. It was the database that I was worried about. I have a homelab with PostgreSQL running. I could have used that but I would have needed to figure out getting that accesible from outside of my home network. Instead of doing that I chose to use Supabase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was using the free plan of Supabase I thought that it was going to hurt me but actually it was very pleasant. I very quickly create two tables. The Supabase interface is very pleasant and easy to work with. I find it much better and easier to work with then the PGAdmin4 interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating my two tables I was able to very quickly setup foreign keys. Now it was time to setup my API key. To authenticate you just need the Supabase project URL and key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with me wanting to use self hosted infrastructure I think there is a time and a place for IAaS. For example, this was just a simple project that took me about 10 hours to write. If I used my own self hosted database I would have increased the length of the project by at least a hour or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many platforms that offer a database. The reason that I went with Supabase over other competitors was because it is open source and self hostable. While I did not use the self hosted option I like having that flexibility so that if my needs grow and I want to continue using Supabase rather then my own database I am able to self host it rather then pay Supabase to host it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am happy that I used Supabase because now I have experience with it. I think it is good practice to try new things because it not only teaches you more but it lets you maybe find something that works better. For now I am going to continue using PostgreSQL for all my projects but Supabase was a nice choice for this project and is a viable option for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/my-experience-with-supabase.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/my-experience-with-supabase.html</guid>
        
        <category>Supabase</category>
        
        <category>Databases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
